Preliminary Inventory to the K. Nagy Collection, 1942-1962
Hoover Institution Archives
K. Nagy Collection,
1942-1962
76064
Nagy, K., collector
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Interview transcripts, reports, clippings, and printed matter, relating to the Hungarian Revolution of 1956, political events in Hungary during World War II, the trial of Edgar Sanders in 1950-1951, and the espionage trial of Oleg Penkovskii and Greville Wynne in 1962.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Penkovskii, Oleg Vladimirovich, 1919-1963.; Sanders, Edgar, 1906-; Wynne, Greville M., 1919-; Espionage, Russian.; Hungarians in foreign countries.; Refugees.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Hungary.; Hungary.; Hungary--History--Revolution, 1956.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation)
Container List
- Miscellaneous documents concerning the Hungarian Revolution of 1956 (Box 1)
- Interviews with Hungarian refugees (in Hungarian)
- Interviews with Hungarian refugees (in English)
- The British press on Hungary [1 of 2], 1956 October-December (clippings)
- The British press on Hungary [2 of 2], 1956 October-December (clippings) (Box 2)
- "Hungarian News Survey" (A Summary of News from Radio and Press Sources), London, 1942-45
- Trial of G. M. Wynne and Penkovsky, 1962 (clippings)
- Trial of Sanders, 1950-1951 (clippings)
- Müvelt Nép, 1956 (organ of Imre Nagy's circle, Hungarian newspaper)
- Rákosi Mátyás: Élete Képekben (Mathew Rakosy: His Life in Photographs), Budapest, 1952
- Magyar Közlöny: A Magyar Népköztársasag Hivatalos Lapja (Hungarian News Release: The Official Paper of the People's Republic of Hungary), Budapest, 1956
- Declassified British government records, 1944-1945 (Box 2)
  Formerly security-classified records of the British government, released in full. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover, thereunder by British office
  - 2011 January release, Political Warfare Executive Weekly Directive for B.B.C. Hungarian Service, September-December 1944 (Box 2)
  - 2011 January release, Political Warfare Executive, South Eastern Europe, Intelligence Section Weekly Intelligence Summary, September 1944 - February 1945 (Box 2)